{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"English","incorrectAnswers":["French","Spanish","Mandarin"],"question":"What is the universally accepted international language of aviation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ophthalmology","incorrectAnswers":["Endocrinology","Cardiology","Nephrology"],"question":"What medical field specializes in the eyes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"That’s my secret, Captain: I’m always angry.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"They call me Mister Tibbs!\"","\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Marvel’s The Avengers'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Karl Mordo","incorrectAnswers":["Odin","Tony Stark","Thor"],"question":"Chiwetel Ejiofor plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tokyo","incorrectAnswers":["Osaka","Kyoto","Sapporo"],"question":"Which Japanese city is served by Narita Airport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dravidian","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Niger–Congo","Afroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Telugu' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cameron","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Aliens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Dachshund","incorrectAnswers":["German Shepherd","Doberman Pinscher","Rottweiler"],"question":"Which German dog breed features short legs and a long body?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sciatic nerve","incorrectAnswers":["Optic nerve","Lumbar plexus","Ulnar nerve"],"question":"Which is the largest nerve in the Human Body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vanuatu","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Dominican Republic","Guinea-Bissau"],"question":"Port Vila is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Merlin","incorrectAnswers":["Gandalf","Dumbledore","Gadzook"],"question":"Which magician was an advisor to King Arthur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"How to Train Your Dragon","incorrectAnswers":["How to Train Your Basilisk","How to Train Your Kraken","How to Train Your Unicorn"],"question":"In which 2010 animated film does Hiccup befriend and then teach an injured mythical creature?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pierce Brosnan","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Roger Moore","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The World is Not Enough?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nicolaus Copernicus","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galilei","Johannes Kepler","Isaac Newton"],"question":"Which Polish astronomer, born in 1473, had his books on heliocentric theory censored by church edict in 1616?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Abu Dhabi","incorrectAnswers":["Rabat","Meccah","Islamabad"],"question":"What is the capital city of United Arab Emirates?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"games and play","incorrectAnswers":["blood serum","the scientific study of baths, bathing and of their application to disease","word origins"],"question":"What is Ludology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Who released the iconic album 'Ziggy Stardust'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydrocarbons","incorrectAnswers":["Gases","Petroleum Spirits","Methylated Spirits"],"question":"What are Petrol, Naphta, Kerosine, Diesel and Oil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kenya","incorrectAnswers":["Ethiopia","Tanzania","Morocco"],"question":"Nairobi is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Uma Thurman","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Kristin Scott Thomas"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Pulp Fiction and Kill Bill Volume 1?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Pierce Brosnan","George Lazenby","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The Man with the Golden Gun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","China","Brazil"],"question":"In what country did the \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Andy Warhol","incorrectAnswers":["Salvador Dali","John Lennon","David Bowie"],"question":"Who designed the album sleeve for The Rolling Stones LP \"Sticky Fingers\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Vietnam","Cambodia"],"question":"Colombo is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"His System Of Wind Force Indicators","incorrectAnswers":["Being the first person to circumnavigate the globe alone","Discovering Hawaii","Surviving adrift at sea for 2 weeks"],"question":"For what is the eighteenth and nineteenth century sailor Sir Francis Beaufort best remembered?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephenie Meyer","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","Brandon Sanderson","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Eclipse'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Who sung the song 'Smooth Criminal'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chesapeake Bay","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco Bay","Hudson Bay","Tampa Bay"],"question":"Which bay is marked by Cape Charles and Cape Henry in Virginia, on its northern and southern sides?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Indus","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Ganges","The Euphrates"],"question":"The ancient city of Mohenjo-daro lies along which river in Pakistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pol Pot","incorrectAnswers":["Tol Pot","Lol Pot","Bol Pot"],"question":"Who was the leader of the Khmer Rouge?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man refuses assistance as he ages and begins to his own mind.","incorrectAnswers":["After awakening from a coma, a former assassin wreaks vengeance on those who betrayed her.","In World War II a group of soldiers go behind enemy lines to rescue a paratrooper.","An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Father?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Augustus","incorrectAnswers":["Nero","Herod","Pilate"],"question":"Who ruled Rome when Christ was born?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dwight Eisenhower","incorrectAnswers":["Benjamin Harrison","Abraham Lincoln ","Franklin Pierce"],"question":"Who was the 34th president of the USA, in term during the period 1953–1961?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An Army Medic refuses to kill and receives the Medal of Honor without firing a shot.","incorrectAnswers":["After his son is captured and taken to Sydney, a clownfish sets out on a journey to bring him home.","A man becomes concerned for his Jewish workforce after witnessing their persecution by the Nazis.","The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Hacksaw Ridge?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Melon","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Apple","Orange"],"question":"What Fruit Is A Cantaloupe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It's Raining Men","incorrectAnswers":["Relax","It Takes Two","Hot Child in the City"],"question":"The Weather Girls had a one hit wonder in 1983 with which song?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jamie Foxx","incorrectAnswers":["Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Django Unchained and Dreamgirls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Moon","incorrectAnswers":["The Sun","Halley's Comet","Mars"],"question":"What celestial object was the first for humankind to set foot on?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Rudolph","incorrectAnswers":["Blitzen","Donner","Dancer"],"question":"Which reindeer isn't mentioned in the poem 'The Night Before Christmas''","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip K. Dick","incorrectAnswers":["Stanisław Lem","Edgar Rice Burroughs","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel L. Jackson","Peter O'Toole","Bruce Willis"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Jack Torrance in The Shining?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Brunei","Japan"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Bigos?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Monaco","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chess","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Life","Monopoly"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must move pieces around a board in an effort to capture their opponent’s pieces?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nauru","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Botswana","Ecuador"],"question":"Yaren District is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Salt","incorrectAnswers":["Sugar","Vinegar","Lemon Juice"],"question":"What is the common name of the chemical compound sodium chloride?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sherry ","incorrectAnswers":["Ginger","Tomatoes","Bread"],"question":"What would you use the solera process on?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Agatha Christie","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Treasure Island'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alien","incorrectAnswers":["Gone with the Wind","A Streetcar Named Desire","Caddyshack"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Ellen Ripley'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ocean Spray","incorrectAnswers":["Land o' Lakes","Minute Maid","Florida's Natural"],"question":"What is the brand name under which Boston lawyer Marcus Urann marketed cranberry sauce in 1912?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"'Earth Song' was originally released by which musician?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Daniel Craig","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in You Only Live Twice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Golden Hind","incorrectAnswers":["The HMS Victory","The Mary Rose","The Black Pearl"],"question":"With Which Ship Did Francis Drake Circumnavigate The World?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["Led Zeppelin","Queen","The Who"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled \"Tusk\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Suffix","incorrectAnswers":["Prefix","Infix","Interfix"],"question":"What word refers to a set of letters placed after the stem of a word?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Motor racing","Tennis","Figure skating"],"question":"With which sport is Haile Gebreselassie associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rock Around The Clock","incorrectAnswers":["Johnny B Goode","Candy Girl","Old Time Rock and Roll"],"question":"Which Bill Haley song became the U.K.'s first Rock and Roll number one?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The t in 'train'","incorrectAnswers":["The y in 'yellow'","The n in 'no'","The m in 'mother'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Definitely Maybe","incorrectAnswers":["What's the Story (Morning Glory)","Parklife","Greatest Hits"],"question":"What Was The First Number One Album For Oasis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Protactinium","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium","Lead","Palladium"],"question":"What is the Chemical Element Pa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Brie Larson","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Jennifer Lawrence","Charlotte Rampling"],"question":"Who won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Ma in Room?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Magical Mystery Tour'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Daniel Craig","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Moonraker?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Prague","incorrectAnswers":["Vienna","Oxford","Budapest"],"question":"Which European city is nicknamed the city of a hundred spires?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Camry","incorrectAnswers":["Giulietta","Escalade","Veyron"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Toyota?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["Henri Matisse","Sandro Botticelli","Georges Seurat"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Three Musicians\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sugar Maple","incorrectAnswers":["American Redbud","Weeping Willow","Elm Tree"],"question":"What is the common name for the tree species Acer saccharum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1970","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1990","1960"],"question":"In Which Year Was The Boeing 747 Put Into Regular Service?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Silmarillion","incorrectAnswers":["The Decameron","Dead Souls","Welcome to the N.H.K."],"question":"In which book does 'Tuor' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cabernet Sauvignon","incorrectAnswers":["Pinot Noir","Chardonnay","Merlot"],"question":"What is the most widely planted grape variety in the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Haiti","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Saint Vincent and the Grenadines","Suriname"],"question":"Port-au-Prince is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert De Niro","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Lorre","Robert Englund","Joe Pesci"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Travis Bickle in Taxi Driver?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Lord of the Rings","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Red Rising","The Hunger Games"],"question":"In which book series does 'Frodo Baggins' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Coven","incorrectAnswers":["A Nest","A Barrow","A Scatter"],"question":"What Is The Name Given To A Group Of Witches?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A kilt","incorrectAnswers":["A kimono","A tuxedo","A dress"],"question":"What item of clothing is traditionally worn with a wide belt as part of Highland dress?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iraq","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Austria","Bosnia & Herzegovina"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of The Erbil Citadel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the song 'Just Can't Get Enough'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ice Hockey","incorrectAnswers":["Figure skating","Motor racing","Athletics"],"question":"With which sport is Wayne Douglas Gretzky associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Banquo","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Macbeth","Macduff","King Duncan"],"question":"Whose ghost appears at the dinner table in \"Macbeth\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Taxi Driver","incorrectAnswers":["The Graduate","Midnight Cowboy","Raging Bull"],"question":"'You talkin to me?' is a line from which 1970's film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","William Shatner","Tori Amos"],"question":"The song 'The Man Who Sold the World' had a well-known cover by Nirvana, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"René Descartes","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","G. W. F. Hegel","Immanuel Kant"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'If you would be a real seeker after truth, it is necessary that at least once in your life you doubt, as far as possible, all things'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Three Imaginary Boys'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"H.G. Wells","incorrectAnswers":["Jules Verne","Aldous Huxley","J.K. Rowling"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Time Machine\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ruby","incorrectAnswers":["Diamond","Sapphire","Emerald"],"question":"In Western cultures, what is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Don't Stop Me Now\" by Queen","incorrectAnswers":["\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"Crazy Train\" by Ozzy Osbourne"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Tonight, I’m gonna have myself a real good time / I feel alive / And the world, I'll turn it inside out, yeah / I'm floating around in ecstasy...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tokyo","incorrectAnswers":["Kyoto","Osaka","Nagoya"],"question":"In which city is Edo Castle located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A groundhog","incorrectAnswers":["A prairie dog","A mole","An armadillo"],"question":"Which animal supposedly predicts whether there will be 6 more weeks of winter or an early spring?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Herbivore","incorrectAnswers":["Vegitarian","Vegivore","Omnivore"],"question":"What name is given to animals which only eat plants?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fudge","incorrectAnswers":["Toffee","Caramel","Marshmallow"],"question":"What is the name of the semisoft sweet good made from sugar, butter & cream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada ","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","China","The USA"],"question":"Which Is The 2nd Largest Country In The World?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Glass","incorrectAnswers":["Cling Film","Diamond","Perspex"],"question":"What see-through substance is made by fusing silica at high temperatures?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Mayflower","incorrectAnswers":["The Mary Rose","The Santa Maria","HMS Victory"],"question":"Of which ship was Miles Standish captain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Swing Life Away\" by Rise Against","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","\"Chimpan-A to Chimpan-Z\" by Troy McClure"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Am I loud and clear, or am I breaking up? / Am I still your charm, or am I just bad luck? / Are we getting closer, or are we just getting more lost?\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Iraq War","incorrectAnswers":["The Vietnam War","The Ukraine War","Gulf War"],"question":"During which conflict did the Abu Ghraib scandal occur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Attica! Attica!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Why don't you come up sometime and see me?\"","\"Well, here's another nice mess you've gotten me into!\"","\"Well, I don’t want to survive. I want to live.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dog Day Afternoon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"0","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","3"],"question":"How Many Humps Has A Dromedary Camel Got?","difficulty":"medium"},